Move it, damn it!
Stay there, you little punks!
Wait till I get my hands on you!
You, bastard!
Yes? Jung Tae-soo speaking.
How have you been?
It's Miran here.
It's been a long time.
I trust you're well.
Wang-jae passed away
this morning...
Hey, you, some dry snacks over
here, huh. Don't forget the beer.
Hey, bring some eats
to the folks over there.
That reminds me.
If not you,
who'd take care of all this.
With Wang-jae gone and everything,
Miran would've had to do
everything herself.
What are you talking about?
Before Wang-jae was
my little sister's husband,
he was my friend, you know?
We were family!
You're straight up,
that's what I like about you.
That's why I always talk
so highly of you.
The way I see it.
When I said I wanted to sit
for the exams,
Wang-jae was the only one
who helped me.
Who dare say I'm wrong!
Frankly, who here didn't
point a finger at me.
Every one of you goddamn guys!
Let it go, Dongwan...
You're drunk.
Drunk? You call someone
telling the truth drunk?
Hey, Pil-ho.
Wang-jae shouldn't have
been the one to die.
But the stinking assholes
sitting around here!
You dumb stupid idiot.
Hey! Hey!
If you're wasted, go home.
- And take a nap you idiot.
- Look here.
Let go. A guy like this has got to
get straightened out a bit.
Let go, let go. Look.
For god sakes,
he's your older brother.
Everybody just go on back to
what you were doing.
God damn it, it left a mark.
Let go.
Is this the way of a funeral house?
The joint's small,
but Wang-jae's prized it.
What's this?
Bring out some good stuff.
I'm on it, can't you see?
Just when he said
he was settling down...
In any case, how've you been?
How I been, how you think I been?
A cop chasing the bad guys
as usual.
You mean you're still resorting to
deadly force to get confessions?
You obviously don't know
the lengths
to pull cuffs round a punk
these days.
Interrogation rooms are a joke,
a real joke.
Looks like Korea's finally
one of the elites, huh?
Like them American TV shows,
they bring in all sorts of
fancy shrinks to put you
on the ringer?
When Columbo said it all,
am I wrong?
That's enough of the small talk.
Whatever was it that
happened to Wang-jae?
What happened blows me away.
You heard the gist of it.
It happened right here.
The help skipped and
Wang-jae ran the shift himself.
Business was jumping though
it only was a weekday.
Couple more beers here please.
Yeah, I'll be right there.
After his mother died and
Miran had the miscarriage,
He tried hard to pull it all together
after he got out.
Heard some kids were causing
some trouble the night
it happened.
You should know since
you're a detective, but
damn kids don't fear
nothing these days.
Scares the damn shit
out of me, them kids.
Older folks know better,
but these kids.
They got no idea
who Oh Wang-jae is.
Wait till I get my hands on you!
- Your ass is mine!
- That's enough!
That's enough, I said!
Don't, don't touch me!
Should've taken a deep breath
then and dropped it.
Trash the stinking place!
That's enough!
You know how Wang-jae could be...
Ran after them outside,
Stay there you little punks!
thinking he'd teach 'em a lesson.
But no champion stays
that way for ever.
No matter what
he might've been before,
he wasn't the Wang-jae of old.
God damn little peckers.
Are you ready?
Go outside!
Why?
We're taking a family portrait today.
Whoever it was that beat up
your brother
sure gave him a chestnut for an eye.
Probably had it coming to him.
Whatever it is, he's still
your brother. Right?
If he only plays right just
half his part,
you wouldn't have to
worry about such things.
Frankly, who do we have to thank for
having to live cooped
up like this, huh?
He's pulling us all down with his
wet dreams of being a damn scholar.
What more have we got to do for him?
Now that he's pissed away everything.
Quiet! He'll hear.
Yeah, I know sir.
Of course, sure, but
we could really use you up here!
Listen up. Cover for me
just a few days, alright? What?
You forgot already that
I was stuck in the car
eating ramen for a week,
when you had your kid?
Why are you digging up
that story now?
My hands are tied up,
don't you see?
Look, whatever it is
you've got going on,
I'll see you in Seoul
in exactly one week.
Captain's shitting on
people all over the place.
Well, let him do what he wants.
Gotta go battery's low.
Got no idea! You take care of it!
1987, A high school Fall picnic
Go! Go!
How far you going!
Heh?
What's this?
This stuff is snake good snake.
No better medicine for a man.
Where'd you get that?
Trapped the slimy bastard
some feet down there.
Bottled it right there myself.
What you waiting for? Pop it open!
You dumb hick.
Not any good to chug it now.
This gets better the longer
you keep it buried.
On this day we shall bury it.
Don't anybody touch it!
And in about 20 years or so...
After we all make it big,
we open it with style.
Alright by me,
since it's good for that.
If it's that good,
I can wait even longer.
Hey, Wang-jae!
Wang-jae!
What's going on?
# Like the wings of a pigeon
# flying the blue sky,
# our spirits soar to the skies above.
- Hey!
- # We all laugh together,
Where you bums think
you're jerking off right now?
# with dreams of a brighter tomorrow.
# Oh, friends forever!
# Oh, joyous minds!
# Hey, happy life!
# Oh, friends forever!
# Oh, joyous minds!
# Hey, happy life!
Where we headed to!
Oh man! Show 'em!
# Like the countless stars in
# the wide night's sky,
# we have all become close friends.
# Let us hold hands together,
# and sing the song of happiness!
# Oh, friends forever!
# Oh, joyous minds!
# Hey, happy life!
Run.
Don't sweat it,
life's full of funny surprises.
Whatever happened there anyway?
My brother was acting
up like a stupid idiot in
front of all them boys
from Onsung High school.
Sorry guys.
No need for that.
A future justice of the peace
shouldn't be resorting to fist fights.
You're gonna save all our skins
later on anyways. That's that then.
But I really gotta take a leak.
How we getting out?
You twit.
Just yell for help to the voices
down there.
And embarrass up to death?
Then what?
Just sing for your lives.
# Baby come back
# Blame it all on me I wish
you were here
# Waiting.
Just a second. Tae-soo, say hello.
He's a detective from Seoul.
Got anything for me to do?
What?
Gotta start looking now.
For what?
For what? To get the bastards
who cut up Wang-jae.
What you gonna get?
You'll stir up more shit
than anything.
Damn town's noisy
as hell as it is.
Tell me. I just heard you say
what you did.
It's not just anybody
we're talking about. It's Wang-jae.
You don't think I'm pissed?
You don't think I'm fucking pissed?
He was my best friend,
best fucking friend!
I said he was my best friend,
you idiot, best friend!
Nobody's pissed more than me,
nobody!
But there's a time for everything,
everything!
Well, I was never any good
at keeping time,
but I'm just gonna skin whoever
put it to Wang-jae.
Hey, hey!
What's with him now?
It's nothing.
That moron.
Let's walk down.
How about you?
Going back today?
No matter how I look at it,
Something's not in place.
I want to see Wang-jae's case
closed myself.
What you worried about
when I'm here?
You don't have the law on your side.
Catching bad guys is what I do.
Remember?
Did Wang-jae act strange lately,
that had you notice?
This is snake booze, snake booze.
Doing something
he ain't done before...
Aren't you going to Seoul?
It's a simple homicide
of a petty mobster.
Though you may think otherwise,
detective.
Hey, Miran!
You know that's not the case.
Tell me just one thing.
Did Wang-jae really
get himself clean?
Hey, give me Wonsuk's number.
Uhm, he hasn't been
around these days...
Yeah, nothing so far, huh?
Yeah, drop by here
after you're done.
Mr. Jang, whatever
kept you so long?
My apologies.
Now where were we?
I believe it was
the special tourism license.
Ah yes, the special license.
So the Onsung
Tourism Bill is now law
- and all that's left is letting people know.
- That's right.
And we've got the casino license.
You did well to get us here.
Thank you.
But this is only the beginning.
Brought this up with you last year...
Yes.
This casino business isn't
child's play, you know.
Getting the license don't solve
all problems.
We can't starting construction,
because
we haven't been able to get
the road permit.
Mr. Jo, I've been on it day
and night the last month...
Don't tell me you've been doing
your best.
Everybody tries and does his best,
but there's only two kinds of people.
Those who does the job
and those who don't.
Why else would I send you my
four best people from Seoul?
Do you understand me?
If the road permit doesn't come
soon, matters will get difficult here.
- Sir, how are you?
- Got a delivery?
- Go on, then.
- See you.
Hey!
Oh, what brings you here?
Came out because I missed
you dearly.
Busy?
Wish I was.
Shall we splash around
in a sauna, then?
Sauna?
Sauna sounds good.
# We met worldly world
# What is your hope?
Which one first, the pinky
or the thumb?
Which one? Pinky? Thumb?
Start with the thumb.
Guess it don't matter much
which goes first.
Look here now, Jang.
I'm the chairman of
the Youth Federation.
Landlord Jang.
You've made your point!
How about doing the tongue first?
Can't concentrate
because of the noise.
That's rushing it a bit, no?
Why you booked up today?
Jang. I'll square up with you.
You know I'm the only heir.
How can the only grandson ever
turn his back on his hometown?
Wait. How about taking
the whole hand?
Can I?
Mr. Jang! Don't forget who backed
you to reach what you are today!
How about going with the heel?
The heel is much more troubling.
Yeah? Go for it then.
Alright.
Mr. Jang. You take my land,
I got nowhere to go.
Humming a song should help a bit,
right?
Who was that again
at the secret service,
grounding everything and feeding
it to the chickens?
This is humanistic compared
to that monster.
Why is it then that you take me
as a fool?
Mr. Jang!
You win, you win.
You baking a cake in there,
bitch, get out here!
I'm coming, I'm coming!
Let's go.
Oh my god, what're you doing?
What bitch? Shoot!
Hey, what's going on?
Someone come in?
Been waiting for me?
You actually take a shit too?
Blow off, OK,
can't you see I'm busy?
So when are they coming?
- Who's they?
- Who they.
All your hard-working stiff
boyfriends.
How the hell should I know that?
Don't get mad at me or anything.
Boozing it up every night
gives you the runs, don't it?
Hey, diarrhea girl, look here.
- You wanna be internet famous?
- Hey, you totally nuts?
Stop it!
I don't know anything!
- Good resolution.
- Crazy bastard.
Ok for underage girls to work
these days?
Can't even go near booze
as far as I know.
- Hey! Hey! You sick bastard!
- Bidets are popular these days.
Don't know? For real?
Still don't know?
You sick dog, stop it.
Alright, alright.
- What? You gonna tell me something?
- I'll tell you.
Heard he's hiding out somewhere
in downtown.
Pissed off!
Hey you! Don't complicate things.
Just answer the questions.
Who the hell are you, a pig?
Pig?
I wanted this to be civilized,
but you don't let me.
Think you remember
a bit better now?
Yes, yes!
Be careful!
You'll hurt yourself.
Don't you even have uncles,
you idiots?
- No, no!
- Grab the rope!
The rope!
Who the hell are these kids anyway?
You should know better than me.
You've been away too long.
This ain't the same Onsung
you know.
Came back after a
decade and find my
ass kicked by a bunch of kids, damn it!
Right after Wang-jae
washed his hands clean
and handed everything
over to Pil-ho,
there was suddenly all this talk
about a casino coming to town.
Should've kept quietly to it instead
of breaking his back with a bar.
Wang-jae and Pil-ho get along OK?
Friends are friends no matter what.
Wang-jae would take care of things
with whatever Pil-ho couldn't fix.
They never brought me in
on any of it.
Sukhwan don't be a soldier no more.
I'll have a talk with the local
chapter.
What? Be real, will you.
What?
What are you going to do, huh?
Put yourself in his shoes
for a second.
The man we're all indebted
to died like a dog.
You want me to do nothing? Huh?
It's killing me too!
At least you guys were
around him all along.
How about me?
Know how it feels to come home
after 10 years
to see your friend
in a goddamn morgue?
Huh?
Shit!
After Donghwan squandered all
we had,
there was only Wang-jae
to help him out.
And it was only Wang-jae
who looked out for me
when I was running into it bad.
But what are you?
I gotta make Wang-jae rest in
peace.
Sukhwan.
Hey can you trace up
those kids' ladder?
Hey, who came down from
Bonjungdong yesterday?
Let go, you asshole!
Ouch! What are you doing?
Bring me up! I'll tell you!
I'll tell you goddamn it!
What are you guys doing here?
You sick useless bastard!
Think about your mother, you...
- You bastard!
- Hey!
You're not my brother, you bastard.
I thought something was strange.
Got no bitch
and always stayed home,
- but always pinching around.
- It's not that, that's not how it is!
If not that then what, what?
Hey, Dong-wan, Dong-wan!
Look at me.
Dong-wan! Look me in the eye.
Hey, Tae-soo.
Really I didn’t know.
Promised me dope
if I named some loose kids.
But I didn't know
that was going to hurt you.
I'm a son of a bitch
if I did that on purpose.
Who made you like this?
Mr. Jang, isn't this too much?
Go over the terms of the contract.
Pledged property is surrendered
when full repayment is not made
by given date.
That's not what you said
when you lent me the money.
How much more generous can I be?
Frankly my rates were better
than a bank's
and I let slide
countless missed payments.
Everybody knows the land price
is going to jump.
So we'll sell when high and
pay back your money.
I'm going to go with
what the contract says.
You bitch's son!
You think it's a secret
what you got up your dirty sleeve,
heh?
Why you all throwing fits now, huh?
You all think you're sitting
on a gold mine?
You fools!
Why'd you borrow my money?
Robbers of the worst kind,
all of you!
- Throw them the hell out!
- You son of a bitch!
A few months ago,
he promised me store space beside
the casino if I helped him out.
Then mother won't have to work
in the market.
And you took that at face value,
huh?
Let it go, will ya?
He's your older brother god sakes.
So, how could you help
Pil-ho out with?
When talk started of a casino
or other,
cops hunkered down
on all of Pil-ho's boys.
With my job being a teacher
to a lot of them,
and Pil-ho having to make a living...
I gave him names
of some fresh faces.
He came to me for my help.
When'd you start shooting up, huh?
Did he know you were on it?
Hey!
Is that all you know of your brother?
I ended up like this...
after all the thank you
visits he made.
Looking like this
who's going to listen to me?
That bastard!
The Youth Federation
chairman knows well
the work Pil-ho and
Wang-jae were doing.
Brother!
Who in the world moves in
the middle of the night?
The night's cool! No traffic!
Can't a man move when he wants?
Call this fresh air?
It's damn freezing out here!
This here's hot chocolate season!
Tell me what happened between
Wang-jae and Pil-ho?
Don't know! Out of my way!
Cooperate and it'll be easy on you.
If delivery came only a bit sooner,
lazy bums.
After Wang-jae passed over
reigns to Pil-ho,
the whole place became a mess.
Wang-jae might have gotten his
start
as a wise guy but he knew
how to run things.
But Pil-ho's just a thug,
he didn't know left from right.
Place was nice and quiet then.
How many times is this now, heh?
Pil-ho then threw everything
up-side-down
Sukhwan, you collected for him
so you should know.
Let me go!
When the hot springs stopped
doing well,
the town was already dying
with nothing but bones and no meat,
- Move it! Get them out of here!
- that's when all hell broke loose
In other words, that's
when opportunity came knocking.
Things picked up real quick,
and then talk traveled fast
that the casino will be letting
in everybody...
Things are really heating up here
with all this about building a casino.
So it's this area here.
And Pil-ho too came around
for a scoop.
But the problems started
with a Mr. Jo.
Casino operators they were
from Seoul
On condition Pil-ho looks
after local matters,
they apparently offered him
a partnership.
That's when Pil-ho started
loan sharking with funds
he got from the people
from Seoul.
It's as if all the worst fears came
true.
When the situation finally came
to that,
who are the people going to
look up to if not Wang-jae?
That's also the last time
I saw him.
Why don't you say
something brother? Heh?
This for the public good.
Wang-jae, you're taking this
all wrong.
I received help from Mr. Jang, too.
That's why you're a problem, too.
There's a problem
and we're looking the other way.
Because we're hoping for something
to trickle down?
Problem, what problem?
It's for the greatest good!
Stop what you're doing.
The whole town's a mess
because of you.
Even for a wise guy,
there's things you can and cannot
suckle on.
What are you a leech?
Sucking blood from this guy
and that guy?
Hey, that's a bit harsh, no?
I'm your own wife's brother!
Hey! It's Wang-jae you're talking to,
Oh Wang-jae!
What's with you guys?
This a classy joint we're in.
Bring some duct tape
if you have any.
This brings back fun memories, heh?
Won't be fun in a while!
You're making a mistake.
Mistake was yours.
But you can save yourself of
more than just a rough ride.
Peel and feast on it.
Still got no idea about
the grave you're digging?
Keep it up and you'll not only lose
the people's, but your own shirt
as well.
Did Pil-ho then take out Wang-jae?
I said that's as far as I know.
But that Pil-ho isn't someone
to be deterred so easily!
You've no right
to be cussing out Pil-ho
since you set the stage for the kill
I'm a victim, too!
Nobody made you use
other people's money for wager.
I didn't know Pil-ho'd treat me
like this.
We were partners, him and me.
How much of this did you know?
First time I'm hearing this.
But you ran for Pil-ho.
I didn't know.
Didn't even know my own brother
turned into a junkie.
Yeah?
Stupid punk!
There's all kinds I'm telling you.
Let me do him.
Hey, lift your head!
Let me go! Stupid idiot!
Just let me kick this kid's ass!
Hey!
Snap out of it!
It's Pil-ho we're after! Huh?
You can give a statement
at the station
if I guarantee your safety, right?
It's late.
I, uhm, feel...
embarrassed to face you.
I'm beat, so just get to the point.
During Ma's 60th birthday party
tomorrow,
can you treat me like your older
brother then?
You know it's not for me or
anything.
Out of consideration for Ma.
Her first born son, a weakling
outside and inside the house.
Have any idea what time it is?
Came to play the bad drunk?
Leave!
Ah, fuck it.
Can't visit the house of my only
friend whenever the hell I want?
Why are you doing this to me?
Why? Why?
Did you ask me why?
Ah, fuck it.
Miran!
Ms. Jang Miran!
Your husband Wang-jae...
It was your older brother,
Pil-ho killed him.
My friend Wang-jae,
my friend Pil-ho killed him!
I told you,
you were making a mistake.
Jang Pil-ho, you...
Hey, asshole!
You didn't keep your word.
You said you'd take care of my sister.
Look at the mess you're in now, huh?
Ah, man...
Situation is getting
progressively worse.
So? What do you
propose should be done?
Given the importance of the matter,
I suggest the matter be dealt with
before word reaches Seoul.
Baldheaded sir!
Just one phone call!
Please? It's real urgent.
I'm telling you.
Just let me charge my cell phone.
Darn that cop!
Sir!
Hey mister!
My neck's on the line!
Keep it down, I said!
They're coming for me!
I mean...
- What the?
- Hey mister! My neck's on the line!
What's this? Ain't this gasoline?
What the fuck he's doing!
Help!
Spare me!
Please spare me!
Spare me! Please spare me!
I said nothing.
You gotta believe me, please.
Help! Please, help!
Jung Tae-soo here.
Get the mix with sand just, right?
Screw ups with the ratios are
what's behind the collapse
of bridges and buildings,
irresponsible bastards!
Brother try wiggling your toes a bit.
Feel alright?
It's all rock solid dry now.
See how I always look out
for your interest?
But you never gave me
any credit for that!
Did I or didn't I tell you to stay put
till I get things ready huh?
Am I one to hog your land?
Am I not one to let you reclaim it
later on?
I just don't get it.
Wanting so much without
making any sacrifices.
You're a traitor.
In any case, no more after today.
I say again but I did nothing wrong.
We're here because
brother took things too far.
You poor.
Alright, pass on my best regards
to Wang-jae.
Wow! Ma traveled back
in a time machine.
That's just
because you won't grow up.
Good enough for the movies then,
There'd be no bigger star
next to me.
You're gleaming
because of the great dress.
Donghwan picked out for you.
But we gotta get going
if we're picking up aunt.
Alright!
Remember this?
Still ways left for 20 years,
but with one gone already.
Looks like one of us
isn't gonna make it either.
Got the green light.
Brought it thinking there'll
be no other chance to talk.
Ma, all this here used to be
farmland.
I can't believe it.
Wouldn't have sold the land
had I known this'd happen.
But boy, it's a nice day today.
Still didn't go back, huh?
Planning to go back with you.
There's a lot left for me to do here.
How many more people's gotta get
hurt?
This is your own hometown, man.
Long time since I changed
my address.
Stop joking around and stop it.
You know?
You guys tried to boss me around
since we were kids.
We didn't try, we did boss you!
Taesoo, Jung Taesoo.
Ok.
If you've got time,
let's go to the sauna.
Say, think you can hack it?
You know what?
I know it's cheesy to kiss ass,
but it's worse to not give credit
where it's due.
Staring at me? What? What?
Drunk in anger?
Burns real hot inside?
Kills ya you're helpless
to an old pushover, huh?
Can't even die
if you don't got the grit.
I'm not going to kill you.
Know why?
You're too much below me.
Isn't forgiveness too a quality
of the strong?
You know? That's real forgiveness.
The strong forgiving the weak.
Know what Taesoo?
It's not the strong who lasts,
but the one that lasts who's strong.
For your ride up!
If you leave him like that,
there's an element of danger.
Should the opening be closed?
Who the hell are you?
I'm the judge and the jury.
I'm the king, damn it!
I'm leaving for Seoul tomorrow.
Oh, yeah?
What do you want me to do?
There's nothing I can do!
One's my brother
and the other my husband.
Heard there's a gathering tonight at
Ondangjung of the casino people.
Hello.
It's me Sukhwan.
Funeral for your mother
and brother go well?
State of things for bade me
from attending.
Did send a fat envelope though.
It's your heart that's important.
It's all war from now.
Something piss you off?
Stop it you scaring me.
But what am I gonna do?
Oh shucks, real busy though tonight
with all the Seoul boys in town.
It's no problem.
We don't care much about time
and place.
Had Donghwan really become
a judge,
he sure would've watched
our backs, huh?
Hey, I may not have a warrant...
but this is at least half legal.
What?
Hey, where's this Jang Pil-ho?
Cheers!
What's all this noise?
Don't worry about it.
Noise is normal in a place like this.
How ya doing? Feel alright?
Running low on gas.
But you got less mileage on ya.
Heh? The hurt don't discriminate
between the old and young.
I'm busy, catch up with ya later.
Ok.
When the job here is done,
you must take some main office
work and help build the organization.
Your hometown's a tourist city...
It's time you shed
your backward image.
I would like to introduce you
to the chairman.
But you're still a little rough
around the edges.
Wonder if that's because you've
done nothing but field work.
I still don't think you fully
appreciate what real business is.
Who's that?
Noise is because of them two?
You disappoint me, Mr. Jang.
Though I did start knowing that
I'd be working with a bunch of hicks,
How can I work losing face like this?
Hell of a big mouth, Asshole.
What? What?
What? This guy?
He's not the chairman or anything.
Shit.
This ain't changing anything
for you or me.
Skinny cowards.
Not taking leftovers here?
Hey, Taesoo.
I lose cuz of you. Driving me nuts.
You breaking my balls hanging
around here, heh?
Come on and have a drink.
Pretty good eats here.
You got good teeth both of you.
Life throws all kinds at ya,
but no need
to dive head first into everything,
right?
Jang Pil-ho, you bastard!
How is it, something hot in your body?
Feels like something's poking?
It's all like that the first time.
Why you always trying to make me
the bad guy?
What?
Wang-jae and you,
why you guys always put me down?
Jealous?
Getting jealous because
your punch bag has sidestepped
you and been crowned king?
Huh?
Fuck it.
Hey, Pil-ho!
How'd we end up like this...
There's nothing between us...
Hey, Pil-ho.
You can never know...
but the winner is
the last one standing...
Hey, Pil-ho.
I remember your hands,
they were always warm, heh?
But technically speaking,
didn't we win?
Donghwan, what do you think?
They did the wrong stuff,
and we beat 'em in actual practice
as well.
They're stinking bums anyway.
Whole days gone and we
got nothing to show for it.
Whatcha mean?
We got this bottle to show for it.
We make it big and in about
20 years we drink it in style.
Wonder what we'll be doing then.
Ah, don't fret about it.
Ain't gonna be a walk
in the park anyway.
What are you, bitch!
Fuck it.
www.moviesubtitles.org